[ people chattering ]
[ women clamoring ]
[ speaking haitian creole ]
[ siren wailing ]
[ motor whirring ]
[ children chattering , shouting ]
[ gunshot ] [ women scream ]
[ shouting in creole ]
[ creole ]
[ man on pa . , indistinct ]
[ continues in creole ]
[ gunshot ]
[ laughing ]
[ shutter snaps ]
[ man speaking french ]
[ man ] amen .
[ speaking french ]
[ man shouts in distance ]
[ people shouting ]
Christophe !
[ pleading in french ] christophe !
[ man narrating ] field notes , dr . Dennis alan ,
Rio negro botanical expedition , August 15 , 1985 .
I arrive at the clearing of the shaman an hango ,
Regarded as the most powerful spiritual man in the amazon .
There 's something strange in the air today .
Even my pilot 's nervous .
If I were superstitious , I 'd say that something was closing in on me .
♪ [ chanting ] the shaman senses it too .
He decides in his own off-the-wall way to show me what it is .
[ grunts ] tell him I 'm very appreciative , that harvard thanks him ,
That his potion will make a good medicine ,
And it will be helpful for many people .
[ translating in spanish ] I 'tome !
[ speaking spanish ]
No , he wants you to drink it . He says he has something he wants you to see .
You know what you 'll see if you drink that shit ? Stars , amigo .
- Let 's get outta here . - Tome .
Like I said , for the road .
It 's good . It 's very good .
Thank you .
[ groaning ]
[ growling ]
[ gasping ]
[ panting ]
[ screaming ] [ growling ]
[ purring ]
Hey .
[ laughing ]
[ wind blowing ]
[ speaking spanish ]
[ out of breath ]
- [ growling ] - [ screams ]
No ! Stop !
Stop ! No !
[ screaming ]
[ gasping ]
[ panting ]
Julio ? [ echo ] julio ?
Julio !
[ echo ] julio !
Hey . Whoa .
I thought you 'd taken off without me . I owe you one , pal .
Hey .
[ birds screeching ]
[ dennis narrating ] something much more evil and powerful ...
Than the shaman or his men has killed my pilot .
I know this as clearly ...
As I feel the darkness and the cold closing in on me .
[ panting ]
[ animal growls ]
[ growling ]
[ groans ]
[ horn honking ]
[ chattering in spanish ] hey !
I 'gringo ! [ laughing ]
Hey ! Hey !
[ laughing hysterically ]
[ dennis narrating ] I 'm only back home for a week ...
When I get a call from my old professor and friend , earl schoonbacher .
He 's a consultant for a big pharmaceutical company ...
And says he has an interesting job offer .
Hi , dennis . This is dr . Cassedy , the head of boston biocorp .
How do you do , sir ? Fine . How do you do ? It 's a pleasure .
Well , I 'm impressed . 200 miles through the amazon on foot alone .
Not alone . They showed him his animal spirit , his totem .
The jaguar guided him back to us safe and sound .
Well , we here at boston biocorp ,
We deal in science and medicine , not magic .
So whether you came back by jaguar or mercedes-benz , I really don 't care .
What I care about is you came back with a sample bag ...
Full of plants and native medicines no one has been able to collect .
- What do you know about zombification ? - Pardon me ?
Zombification- - the process of making zombies , the living dead .
Uh , just what I 've seen on thelate show .
This is the death certificate of christophe durand .
And the doctor 's report .
" mr . Durand displayed negative pulse ,
" no heartbeat , no respirations , no pupil dilation ,
No brain waves , no response to pain , and he was buried . "
He was put into a coffin and buried .
You notice the date on that death certificate . It 's seven years ago .
This photograph was taken one week ago at a clinic in port-au-prince , haiti .
That man is christophe durand- -
The same and very much alive .
Maybe durand had a twin . [ schoonbacher ] no .
- Hospital error . You know , right name , wrong corpse . - No .
No , we had it verified by dr . Duchamps at the clinic ,
Now , if you don 't like the word " zombie , " you can choose another word .
But the fact is somebody brought him back from the grave .
And I wanna know how they did it .
You really believe this ?
The haitians surely do .
A drug . It has to be a drug then , right ?
Anesthesia . That 's what I was thinking .
A totally new anesthetic that could revolutionize medicine .
Now , what if this zombie drug could be discovered ?
40,000 to 50,000 lives a year are lost on the operating table ,
And not because of surgery , but because of anesthetic shock .
40,000 to 50,000 lives a year could be saved in the us . Alone , dr . Alan .
And more worldwide , if properly marketed .
[ schoonbacher ] it could be something more complicated than drugs .
It could be the proof , perhaps , of the soul .
Come on , schoonie , where 's the location of the soul- -
Under the hood next to the battery ?
No . The soul begins and ends with the brain .
This drug- - this is something totally new .
We don 't have anything that can put somebody in , then back out , of death .
And all we gotta do is go and get it .
[ woman on pa . , indistinct ] [ crowd chattering ]
[ dennis narrating ] this is one of the poorest countries in the world .
It has revolution in the air . It 's got a ruthless dictator in the palace .
So I had expected a certain sense of oppression .
What I hadn 't expected was that the dark presence from the amazon ...
Would instantly come over me here ,
As real as a cold hand falling on my shoulder .
And I also didn 't expect dr . Duchamps to look like ...
Dr. Duchamps did .
Dr. Duchamps . Bonjour .
Bonjour .
Je m 'appelle- - dennis alan , I know .
Yes . I guess I am an easy face in this crowd .
Oh , I would have known you even in- -
Excuse me ? It would be better if we talk inside .
Those were the tonton macoutes . They know you are here , of course .
[ man screaming ]
[ speaking french ]
You sure handcuffs are the best idea here ?
500 patients , three doctors , 15 nurses . Ah .
A week 's supply of thorazine .
Handcuffs are the only thing duvalier makes sure ...
Haiti has enough of .
This is margrite .
I was expecting- -
After an illness of three days , margrite died and was buried in a village ceremony .
No death certificate , but we have witnesses .
That was 15 years ago .
Last August , she was found wandering aimlessly in the marketplace .
Her brother identified her by her birthmark .
A classic zombie .
Bonjour , margrite .
[ speaking french ]
[ woman 's voice shrieking ]
Well , she sure can 't tell us anything .
I understand that christophe durand- - the man whose death certificate I saw- -
He can speak , right ? Yes . He even speaks some english .
Christophe is unique . Much of his memory is intact .
I 'd like to see him right away .
♪ [ drumming ] ♪ [ women singing in creole ]
[ dennis narrating ] a warning- - that 's what I felt in those eyes .
I didn 't know of what , but it chilled me to the bone .
Marielle took me to see a man who is very powerful in politics and in voodoo .
He 's a full voodoo priest ,
But he also runs a nightclub for tourists .
In fact , lucien celine does a little bit of everything ,
Except give out information .
You 've come on a good night , monsieur .
Tonight the spirits are happy .
We asked about christophe durand .
[ marielle ] lucien , why are you being so difficult ?
You have people all over the island .
Certainly , someone must have seen christophe by now .
Perhaps , but what people see and what they say ...
Are very different matters .
Haiti is full of contradictions , dr . Alan .
These dancers , for instance , they don 't bleed , and they don 't burn .
Tonight we are calling down erzulie , the goddess of love .
You will dance tonight ? No , lucien , I will not .
- You will . - No .
- You all right ? - You have business to discuss .
If you won 't help , we 'll go to christophe 's village tomorrow .
She 'll be fine . She 'll be fine .
♪ [ drumming , singing continue ]
[ man 's voice growling ]
- [ growling ] - [ screaming ]
Yes , he is the one to watch- - captain peytraud .
He plays at being abokor- - the black magician .
He is beneath contempt .
He 's the chief of the tonton macoutes , duvalier 's secret police .
You have seen him before , perhaps , hmm ?
Yeah , someplace . Be careful , my friend .
In haiti , there are secrets we keep even from ourselves .
[ dennis ] hey .
Marielle- - yes .
Favorite of erzulie .
♪ [ drumming , singing continue ]
For marielle , possession is as natural as breathing .
[ groans ]
[ groaning ]
[ shouts in creole ]
[ whimpers ]
Watch it .
[ creole ]
Are you all right ?
[ crowd applauding ]
[ dennis narrating ] marielle never mentioned what had happened the night before .
But from what I knew of possession , she probably didn 't even remember it .
Maybe it was just as well . The village mambo is just up the road .
We asked around christophe 's village , but no one- -
Not even the village voodoo priestess- - would help .
I told you . He is dead . What should I know about the dead ?
The whereabouts of christophe remained a mystery until his sister found us .
Cimetiére .
Let 's go .
[ vehicle approaching ]
[ engine stops ]
What his sister said makes sense .
Christophe is obsessed with death . We will find him .
That 's what you said about the last three graveyards .
[ footsteps running ]
Christophe !
[ bleating ]
Well , this is ridiculous . Let 's get outta here .
- [ shouts ] - [ screams ]
Oh , shit !
Oh , shit . Are you okay ?
[ shouting , chattering ]
Holy shit . They were just grave robbers .
Grave robbers , huh ? That makes me feel a lot better .
You should have seen your face . [ laughing ]
You think this is funny ?
Let 's stop jacking around , huh ?
We 're not going to find christophe tonight , if he 's even alive .
What do you meanif ? You saw the photographs .
For all I know , those photos were taken before he died .
Just what are you trying to say ?
Okay , you 're my only contact here in haiti , right ?
First , you let the evidence go , and then we spend a whole lot of time getting nowhere .
You- - yes , nowhere !
You think I 'm doing this for my health , huh ? I think this is a scam .
I 'm not blaming you . I 've seen the clinic . I know how desperately you need funds .
But do you think cassedy and his corporation ...
Are gonna shell out money for nothing ?
You think this is about money ? Yeah .
The way professor schoonbacher spoke of you ,
It was as though you could walk on water .
Now I know why . Shit floats .
Yeah , well , why the hell are you getting involved , huh ?
Will you talk to me ? Christophe !
Christophe . It 's me , dr . Duchamps .
You remember me , don 't you ?
I remember .
This is dr . Alan .
He 's here to ask you some questions .
Christophe ,
I need you to remember what happened before ... You died .
You spoke about it once to me .
I remember it all- -
The coffin , the- - the burial .
I-I saw it all .
Were you sick ?
What was it that you felt- - the symptoms ?
I heard the dirt falling , falling over me .
The darkness pressed me down .
[ speaking french ]
He says thebokor , the one that made him like this ,
Beats him with a whip .
Thebokortook his soul and sealed it away .
He makes me do evil things .
I 'm no longer free . He sends me to people 's dreams .
I 'll-I 'll need to ... Run a blood test .
I 'd like to get a thumbprint . No , I cannot take him back to the clinic .
This is my place , not with the living .
He will find me !
No . Christophe , you 're not dead !
Whatever they did to you , they did it to trick you into thinking that .
You have a good memory . Tell us what you remember ...
So we can stop thebokors from doing this to anybody else .
Help us , christophe .
It 's a powder .
A poison ...
Run through the skin ...
To the soul .
Christophe . No , leave him .
Through the skin . A powder .
[ people chattering ]
♪ [ radio : Afro-cuban ]
[ flies buzzing ]
[ man whispers ] hey , blanc .
♪ [ man chanting in creole ]
♪ [ drumming ] [ crowd cheering ]
[ bell ringing ] ♪ [ people singing ]
[ singing continues ]
[ speaking french ]
Lucien , we need to ask for your help one more time .
We found christophe . He told us about the poison .
Not another word .
Let 's go inside .
If you blunder into this , my people get hurt .
The world should know what is happening here .
You see , she is an idealist .
She simply does not understand how dangerous these times have become .
What I 'm after is going to save too many lives . I 'm not gonna back off .
I know you know the man that makes the powder .
One name , just one .
[ exhales ]
[ crowd shouting , cheering ] ♪ [ jukebox : Haitian ]
The one in the hat is our man , I think .
Louis mozart ? This is important ?
My friend represents powerful interests- - rich american interests .
American ? That 's right .
They have an enemy they would like to turn into a zombie .
A zombie , huh ? [ laughing ]
That is all ? That 's all .
$ 100 .
You 've come to the right place . Your enemy is as good as dead .
I will catch his soul like a spider catches a fly in his web ...
And pop it in acanari ...
Like this one .
You keep the zombie 's soul sealed up .
It makes the flesh your slave .
It gives you power .
You send it into people 's dreams .
Whose soul is that ?
This place 's previous owner . [ laughing ]
Is that right ?
$ 100 .
I cast a spell- - tocoup d 'airtonight .
It 's not the spell that I want .
What I 'm after is the powder .
Thecoup poudre ?
Some say there is such a thing . Some say it .
I guess celine was wrong . This guy can 't help us out . I 'm sorry .
Celine ?
Lucien celine ?
Well , of course . Of course .
Lucien and me , we are like that .
A man should help his friends .
- $ 1,000 . - [ scoffs ]
- 700 . - 400 tops .
For celine , 500 .
All right . Let 's see what you got .
I have some powder already prepared .
You like it , blanc , huh ? It is beautiful , eh ?
Come in .
With this powder , you must be very careful .
I make it so there is no second chance .
[ laughing ] $ 500 , eh ?
How do we know it works ?
- You want proof ? - Yeah .
Marie ! [ speaking creole ]
[ goat bleating ]
[ laughing ] don 't worry .
You have enough for 10 zombies .
[ laughs ]
Yes . [ laughing ]
[ bleating ] [ laughing ]
You are very beautiful .
Are you looking for work ?
He may keep you better ,
But I will love you longer .
So you see , blanc .
No second chance , eh ? So , the money .
The money .
That you get tomorrow when I see you raise the goat from the dead .
I wanna see the goat alive again .
Zombies , remember ?
[ dennis narrating ] it 's too dangerous to wait at the hotel ,
So we lose ourselves in a nearby pilgrimage .
And I realized that though I came for the powder ,
I 'm getting into something much , much more .
You know , I still have a hard time putting you and all that stuff together .
I was brought up in the faith .
My father was ahoungan .
I was dedicated to erzulie at four .
First ridden- - possessed , if you will- - at eight .
There is great beauty and compassion in it .
Oh , yeah . I can understand that .
But you 're a psychiatrist first .
There is no conflict between my science and my faith .
You can give it whatever words you will ,
But in haiti our god is not just in his heaven .
He 's in our bodies , our flesh .
There 's something you should see .
[ woman speaking creole ]
[ woman praying in french ]
[ dennis ] what is this ceremony- - voodoo or catholic ?
Haiti is 85 % catholic , but 110 % voodoo .
For us , erzulie and the virgin mary are the same .
[ crowd chattering ]
[ no audible dialogue ]
[ insects buzzing , chirping ] [ frogs croaking ]
[ moaning ]
[ dennis murmuring ]
[ gasps ]
[ panting ]
[ christophe ] blanc .
Blanc ?
Blanc .
[ hushed screeching ]
[ screeching continues ]
[ bone cracks ]
- [ screaming ] - [ screeching ]
[ screaming continues ] [ bride laughing ]
Are you all right , dennis ?
Yeah . It was just a dream . I had a bad dream .
[ crowd chattering ] ♪ [ drumming ]
[ dennis narrating ] she tells me this is one of the cathedrals of haiti .
A place not only of great beauty , but of great spirit as well .
And maybe the place is magic .
These waters are healing .
[ man on radio ] this is wwbc in miami reporting . The word is official now .
Responding to several months of growing demonstrations ,
The duvalier government in haiti has declared martial law throughout that troubled land .
Police and military units have imposed a strict curfew from sundown to sunup .
[ dennis narrating ] it was crazy .
One minute to be in such beauty and peace ,
The next , surrounded by secret police , the tonton macoutes .
And strangest of all , in the middle of all of this ,
I couldn 't get my mind off the zombie , christophe .
Why would they do such a thing to him ?
Why would they make anybody a zombie ?
Christophe is more than just a patient to you . You knew him from somewhere before .
No , but I knew of him . He was just a grade-school teacher . No one important .
But he wasn 't afraid to speak out for the people , for freedom .
He was very much admired . That 's why they made him what he is .
Instead of inspiring courage , now he only inspires fear .
[ bangs on car ] dr . Alan , come with me , please .
Hey- -
Dr. Alan . Come with me now . All right .
All right . Just take it easy . Take it ea- - I 'll be all right .
[ man sobbing ]
[ man # 2 shouting ]
[ shouting ] [ pleading ]
Ah , dr . Alan .
That 's right . Why are you in haiti , dr . Alan ?
Like it says there on the passport- -
I 'm a tourist . I came to see the sights .
Yes . Happy , happy , happy island people .
Then why visit an insane asylum ?
I 'm an anthropologist .
It 's a tax write-off .
Hope you 're not with the I.Rs. [ man sobbing ]
Did you know this woman , marielle duchamps , is a radical ?
So was her father .
He was ... Misplaced .
Did you know that ?
No , I didn 't know that .
So is this man christophe durand .
Christophe who ?
The man you met in the graveyard .
Graveyard ? I don 't know what you 're talking about . [ man screaming ]
You 're not a very good liar , dr . Alan .
Look , I 'm a tourist .
I haven 't done anything wrong .
Do you mind if I go now ?
[ screaming continues ]
This country lives on the edge , dr . Alan .
One weakness in the wrong place , and over it goes right back into slavery again .
Just like with the french . Look , I 'm not- -
The United States would like anarchy here , I 'm sure .
Well , this isn 't grenada , dr . Alan .
I 'm here now .
There are people like me ...
That make sure that doesn 't happen .
You remember that .
[ man screaming , sobbing ]
- [ shrieking ] - ♪ [ afro-cuban ]
♪ [ continues ]
Dennis , you don 't have to prove anything to me .
That wasn 't just a note they slipped under your door .
It might be better if we waited another day . We haven 't got another day .
As long as we 're out of the city , we 're okay .
[ chattering ]
Come , come , come , come .
Come , come , come . We are celebrating my success .
To good fortune .
So , how 's the goat ?
Oh , business before pleasure , huh ?
The american way , no ?
[ speaking creole ] you saw it die yourself , but it walks .
Nice animal .
You like him ? I throw him in . No charge , huh ?
Americans .
The money for the powder , as we agreed . Oh , okay .
You see , even in america , they know me .
They come for my work .
[ laughing ] [ mocking laugh ]
You 're an idiot .
My powders work .
Maybe I cast a spell on you .
You wanna know what I think of your powders ?
Careful , blanc . No second chance .
Dennis !
It 's piss .
You 're a dead man .
[ people exclaiming , chattering ]
Dennis , just what do think you were doing in there ?
We 've gotta stall for a little time .
What do you know about radiator caps ?
What is it , some macho death wish ?
My god , what if it had been poison ?
It was . Rat poison probably .
Give me your hand . See your palm ?
See the coin and ...
Poof !
See the poison he really gave me ?
Tricks of the trade .
Here he comes . Wait in the car .
You are still alive .
Yeah , I noticed .
I can make it- - the powder you want .
No tricks this time , blanc . $ 1,000 .
The zombie poison- - thecoup poudre . All right .
But there are rules .
You must make it with me .
There is no other way .
[ insects buzzing ]
For strong work , fresh bones . Quickly .
We work here .
You start .
Don 't worry . They never bury them deep here .
That is why I use this place .
[ panting ] this isn 't a kid , is it ?
No , no . This is not a child .
No , no , no .
A real prize , this one .
A sorceress .
- [ fly buzzes ] - when she lived , she had great power .
Now , she is just easier to carry .
[ gasps ]
[ screech echoes ]
Dennis ?
Eh . It stinks .
We will start tomorrow night . Now we get out of here .
Let 's go .
I think I still have some of my father 's old shirts .
Maybe one will fit you .
- This shirt 's fine . - No , it isn 't .
[ gasps ] no ! No !
[ marielle ] let go of me !
[ grunts ] get in the jeep !
[ marielle ] dennis !
[ air hissing ]
[ coughing , gagging ]
[ hissing ] [ gasping ]
You 've got a pretty face .
[ gagging , gasping ]
The girls must like it . Do you like it ?
Your pretty white face .
I asked you a question .
Yeah , I like it .
I like it too .
I leave the face .
You made your point .
I 'm on the next plane . I swear .
Not good enough now . Too late .
You were warned .
I warned you .
I 'm a us . Citizen . Think about that .
I don 't see the ambassador here . Do you ?
I 'm in medical research . There 's a lot of money in it .
There 's plenty for you . I don 't want money .
Yeah ? What do you want ?
I wanna hear you scream .
[ loud bang ]
[ stammering ] ah , no . Okay .
[ quavering voice ] okay . Okay .
You wanna hear me scream ? I 'll scream . [ screams ]
- [ gasps ] - again !
[ screaming ]
Not good enough .
[ scream continues ]
[ man on pa . , in french ]
[ shouting , laughing ]
Dennis !
[ whimpering ]
[ dennis narrating ] for three days , marielle has been my guardian angel- -
Hiding me , nursing me back to health .
The wound peytraud inflicted was struck for fear , not injury .
I 'm alive , intact .
She told me this morning that she wants me to go before they kill me .
But I can 't do that .
[ groans ]
You shouldn 't be out here like this . You shouldn 't even be walking .
This recipe took a thousand years to get right .
I wanna learn it .
[ groans ] rest .
He just went through the scrotum , right ?
A little pain , a little terror .
He scared me , okay ?
- [ croaks ] - [ dennis narrating ] the ingredients of the powder ...
Are terrifically varied .
There is the poisonous sea toad , bufo marinus .
The same animal lucrezia borgia used .
Made even more toxic by frightening it with a stinging sea worm .
And the puffer fish , which produces one of nature 's ...
Most powerful poisons , tetrodotoxin .
Plus a whole pharmacy of herbs , minerals- -
Charred then ground and mixed with a skill that 's astonishing .
All this is woven together with a net of magic beyond anything we know .
The process will take three days and nights .
Already , there 's no doubt in my mind that for all his joking ,
Mozart could give any harvard phd . A run for his money .
[ mozart ] you cannot give the powder in food .
That would kill completely .
The flesh would never rise to serve you .
[ slashing , picking ]
Squeeze . The bones are brittle . It will come .
[ straining , panting ]
This is the last .
Soon , it is done . A good work .
It is a very frightening thing , blanc ,
The first time you can tell good from bad .
Then after a while , it is the very thing that sets you free .
It must be buried with her for one more day .
You must want this enemy of yours pretty badly ...
To go through such pains , blanc .
I 'm all right .
Did he take your woman or steal your money ? No .
Then why would you stand up to a crazy man like peytraud ?
Oh , yes . I hear these things .
The poison 's not for him . The poison 's for nobody .
I wanna use the poison for good , to help people who are sick .
[ laughing ]
My poison can be used in such a way , huh ?
Yeah , I think so .
I think it can be known all over the world .
You will tell them about me ?
You will tell them the name of louis mozart ?
And they will know my work all over the world , huh ?
All right , blanc , come back in 24 hours and you will have your powder .
[ no audible dialogue ]
[ dennis narrating ] twenty-four hours usually doesn 't seem like a long time .
In more relaxed times , I felt a day go by like an hour .
But as sweet as marielle was ,
The day and night at the beach house lasted a lifetime .
- Take me . - Get outta here !
[ growling ]
[ clattering ]
Dr. Alan ?
[ pounding continues ]
[ screaming ]
[ bride cackling ]
[ screams ]
[ gasps ]
[ panting ]
[ whispering ] marielle ? Marielle ?
We gotta get out of here .
[ whimpers ] [ slamming ]
[ shouting ]
What the hell- - not this time , dr . Alan . We 're beyond that now .
[ prisoners pleading ]
Thesecanarihold the souls of those who were masters in the realm of the spirits .
Now their spirits serve me .
She knows I 'm telling the truth , that such things are possible .
I know the price you will pay for what you have done .
The photographs we took today are quite convincing .
If you return , you 'll be tried for the murder of christophe 's sister .
The courts will take your life .
But that will be only the beginning .
After you 're dead , I 'll take your soul .
What 'll happen to marielle ?
You go home .
She 's home . She 's haitian .
I have no reason to hurt her once you 're gone .
Just leave , dennis .
It is the only way .
By the way , dr . Alan ,
What did you dream about this afternoon ?
A woman in your arms ? The sea at your doorstep ?
No , you dreamt of me and of the grave .
I know because I was there .
And I can be there every time you close your eyes .
The pain I cause you in the room upstairs ...
Is nothing to the pain I can cause in your own mind .
Remember that , dr . Alan .
[ man speaking french ]
[ handcuffs clatter ]
[ people chattering ]
You promised me a thousand dollars .
Did you forget your promise ?
No . I haven 't got it . They took all my money .
Well ,
Take it anyway .
But you will tell them about me , blanc .
You will make them know my name .
I will .
I 'll let ' em know you 're a man to be trusted .
[ engines powering up ]
On account , eh ?
[ laughs ] fair enough .
[ typing on keyboard ]
[ cassedy ] you used baboons , right ? That 's right .
Put the powder in the palms . It went right into the blood .
Ten to 20 minutes later , they were dead . Or , at least , they looked dead .
My god . Are these numbers accurate ? Oh , yeah .
I mean , the shift seems radical . I know , but it 's double-blind , triple-checked .
These are typical brain scans from some of our subjects .
It 's very focused . It targets only certain areas of the brain .
Area of vital functions : Breathing , heart rate .
It looks like somebody turned it off with a switch .
But here in the areas of the brain controlling ...
Sensory awareness , thoughts and emotions ,
Bang .
So the animals know what 's happening to them .
Yeah , the entire time . A man would too .
You 'd hear , see , maybe even feel , think .
But you couldn 't do anything about it . You 'd just lie there , looking- -
Dead . And be buried .
But you 'd be alive .
[ dennis narrating ] and , I reminded myself ,
The tests revealed the powder wore off after 12 hours or so ,
Leaving the victim completely normal again .
Except by then , he would be six feet under in the airless black ,
Clawing and screaming with no one to hear his suffocation . Twist of lime ?
Thanks .
[ cassedy ] boy , it 's incredible how- - how rumor 's spreading .
It 's unbelievable . The company stock closed up a point and a half today .
All based on rumor about what dennis has brought back . Thank you , darling .
[ mrs . Cassedy ] I 'm just glad you got out all right .
The news says that the whole country 's in turmoil .
Yeah , I guess it is .
So we 're kicking around a name for the product today .
I can 't believe I actually employ people who want to call an anesthetic " zombanol . "
[ both laughing ] I mean- -
That 's ... Really good .
I gotta get some air .
Excuse me for a minute .
It 's all right .
We need to talk .
Something 's wrong . I can feel it .
I 've been trying to call for three days , day and night , and there 's no answer .
- She could be away . - Yeah , and she could be in trouble too .
I gotta go back there . Listen to me .
There 's a door to the mystical , and you 've just walked through it .
Right now , you are very vulnerable . I wouldn 't go back to haiti .
You 'd be a grade-school boy in a world of nobel prize winners .
I 'd stay as far away from haiti as I could .
♪ [ drumming ]
What you have done is a major breakthrough .
It 's quite mind-boggling .
The only thing I don 't understand is how did christophe durand survive ?
How was he able to speak ?
Alex ?
Well , as far as we can tell , somehow- - I don 't know how- -
Someone dug him out of the grave so no brain damage occurred .
Is something wrong with your soup ?
No , I- - no , it 's all right . I- - I 'm just not hungry .
Elbert , dr . Alan is finished with his soup .
Perhaps monsieur would like salad instead ?
No . I , uh , I 've been having some stomach problems .
Occupational hazard . Dysentery ,
Botfly , malaria .
[ chiming ] a toast ? A toast ?
To dennis .
To his adventures and to this marvelous discovery .
He rang to a new- - to a new- -
Debra ? Sit down , debra .
[ glass crunching ]
[ grunting ]
[ peytraud 's voice ] you 're going to die ! You 've been warned !
You 're going to die !
- Debra ? Debra . - [ screaming ]
Oh , my god ! It 's a seizure . Debra ?
[ screaming continues ]
Oh , my- - oh , my god . Debbie ? Here .
Oh , my god . Debbie , listen to me .
It 's all right . It 's a seizure .
It 'll be all right , dear . It 's gonna be all right , debbie .
[ screaming continues ] debbie ! Debra ?
[ dennis narrating ] he 's going to get to me wherever I am .
I know that now . I 've stolen his darkest and most powerful secret .
He 'll wanna get even , and if he can 't get me , he 'll go for marielle .
[ man on pa . ] welcome to port-au-prince airport . Please have your passport ready .
Hey , I 'm a us . Citizen !
I 'm a us . Citizen ! [ man on pa . ] the airport is under military control .
There will be no taking of pictures in the airport .
[ shouting ] [ tires screech ]
- Hey ! Somebody ! - [ man shouts in french ]
Lucien ?
[ dennis narrating ] lucien 's switch play ...
Snatched me from under the nose of the tonton macoutes .
♪ [ drumming , chanting ]
Marielle was safe . She was guarded by his men at her clinic , he said .
But for mozart and me , it was a different matter .
This will give you some protection . That 's all .
Just like your scientific objectivity . [ gourd rattling ]
In this country , I haven 't felt protected by anything .
You don 't know what hasn 't gotten to you .
[ gourd rattling ]
I 'm not a afraid for myself . A good thing .
Up .
♪ [ drumming continues ]
[ lucien ] just remember , when the battle comes , it won 't be fought in the streets ,
It 'll be fought in your mind , in your soul .
Marielle was right . This must end .
These people- - peytraud , duvalier- -
They 're not haiti , they are mad dogs .
Their madness must stop .
You 're making a mistake !
The president and me , we are like this ! Like this !
[ blood pouring ]
Something 's wrong , isn 't it ?
We are in our spirits hands now , you and I.
Remember , whatever happens ,
Death is not the end . [ chuckles , coughs ]
Lucien ? Lucien ? [ coughing increases ]
[ gasping , gagging ]
[ sputtering , choking ] come on , lucien . Come on .
Oh , no .
- [ chattering ] - oh , fuck !
[ shudders ]
Uh !
[ muttering , groaning ]
[ dennis panting ]
Help me ! [ shouts ]
I 've been poisoned ! No , no , no , no , no .
[ man speaking creole ]
A doctor !
[ garbled speech ]
[ whimpering , panting ]
Hey ! Hey !
[ people exclaiming , shouting ]
[ heart pounding ]
[ woman speaking creole ] don 't- - don 't let them bury me .
I 'm not dead !
[ gasping ]
Anything ? Pressure ? Pulse ? Nothing .
[ sighs ]
We lost him .
Write the time on the tag .
We 'll notify the embassy tomorrow .
No need for that , doctor .
I 've made all the arrangements .
Whatever .
He 's dead . I trust somebody on your end will take care of the proper paperwork .
No , no , no . No rest .
You 'll see it all .
You 'll feel it- - the cold in the coffin .
It is worse . Much , much worse .
[ chuckling ]
Lucien celine , the greathoungan ,
He serves me now too .
Lucien can 't protect you . I hold him fast !
Lucien will turn your blood to worms !
Oh , yeah ? Do you hear me , blanc ?
Her head will be taken as an offering tonight !
No , wait !
To keep you company .
[ hammering ]
[ peytraud ] when you wake up , scream , dr . Alan .
Scream all you want . There is no escape from the grave .
[ insects buzzing ]
[ frogs croaking ]
[ dennis gasping ]
[ shuddering , gasping ]
[ gasping ] help me ! Help !
[ screams ]
[ screaming continues ]
[ gasping ]
[ scratching ] yeah ! Here ! Here !
[ dennis straining ] here !
[ screaming ] oh , god !
[ dennis continues yelling ]
You 're alive !
You 're alive .
Peytraud has your soul .
[ whimpering , shuddering ] [ speaking creole ]
I know . It 's bad , the poison .
You see things the living can 't see !
[ man on pa . Speaking french ]
♪ [ drumming ]
[ man on radio ] this is wwbc in miami reporting .
We 've just received word from port-au-prince , haiti , that baby doc duvalier ,
His wife michelle and his entire family ...
Are en route to port-au-prince airport .
It was an unannounced move happening in the middle of the night ,
And no one knows what it means for sure .
It is confirmed now that the duvaliers are fleeing haiti .
[ cheering ] the scene at the airport was one of barely controlled panic- -
[ announcer continues , indistinct ]
Word now is that the fires of revolution are sweeping the country ...
As news reaches the smaller towns and villages .
[ continues , indistinct ] [ crowd chanting ]
[ crowd shouting , cheering ]
[ man shouting in french ]
- [ crowd chanting ] - [ man shouting in french ]
[ crowd shouting , chanting ]
[ marielle ] where is your power now ?
Theloathemselves are having their vengeance !
[ groans ]
[ crowd chanting ]
[ crowd shouting ]
[ groans ]
Your soul is mine .
Get up , dr . Alan . I control your thoughts now .
Get up !
[ coughing ]
[ scraping against floor ]
[ marielle 's voice ] dennis .
Dennis . Help me .
Marielle ? [ marielle ] help me !
Help me ! Marielle ?
Dennis ! Quick ! Don 't leave .
Help me ! Help me !
Dennis ! [ whimpering ]
It was your fault !
- It was your work . - It was your work .
That caused this .
It was your work that caused this .
[ screaming ]
[ groaning , shrieking ]
[ gasping ]
Whoa !
[ screams ]
[ panting ]
Peytraud .
[ clangs ]
Peytraud !
[ marielle ] dennis .
[ grunting ]
[ groans ]
[ screaming ]
[ dennis screaming ]
Peytraud .
No !
- Help us , lucien . Please ! - No !
[ groaning ]
[ growling ]
[ whimpering ]
[ screaming ]
[ marielle gasping ]
Hold on a second . I 'm not going to leave that thing in one piece .
[ door creaks , closes ]
[ muffled screeching ]
[ screeching ]
[ yelling ]
No rest for you !
- No rest for you ! - [ groans ]
You 're coming with me !
You 're coming with me to hell !
Fuck you !
Son of a bitch !
I 'm tired of this shit !
- What do you want ? - I wanna hear you scream .
- No ! - Yes !
[ peytraud screaming ]
Den ? You all right ?
[ crowd chanting in distance ]
The nightmare is over , den . It 's over .
[ chanting continues ]
[ crowd cheering ]